Fairfax, VA 22031 (818) 671-8222 christopherdenq@gmail.com

# **CHRISTOPHER DENO**

cdenq.github.io github.com/cdenq linkedin.com/in/christopherdenq

# **SUMMARY**

Experience with big data analytics, machine learning, database engineering, and full-stack software development. Unique background in art market confers drive to understand topics holistically, strong prioritization of product sense, and ample work-experience on diverse teams. Avid selflearner and serial project-builder who strives to constantly grow, empower others, and add value to the community.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Foothill College** 

Los Altos Hills, CA

Associates of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science

April 2022 – September 2022

**Honors:** Business Innovation Challenge, 2022 (\$500 for risk prediction ML prototype)

Course Topics: Statistics/Probability, Multivariate Calculus, OOP Programming, Cloud Computing

University of Pennsylvania, College of Arts and Sciences

Philadelphia, PA

Bootcamp Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization

September 2021 – March 2022

Bachelor of Arts, Double Major in Philosophy and Art History

August 2015 – May 2021

Honors: John C. Parker Fellowship, 2016 (\$500 for statistical research in game theory model)

Course Topics: Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Database Engineering/Pipelines, Server Deployment, Fullstack Software Development

## SKILLS AND FRAMEWORKS

Languages: Python (OOP), Java, SQL (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), HTML/CSS/JS, APIs, Git

SKLearn, Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scipy, web-scraping **Machine Learning:** 

Cloud & DevOps: Google GCP, Google Collab, Hadoop/Spark, Docker, Github Pages, AWS, Microsoft Azure Tableau, Google Sheets/Apps Script, Google Suite, Excel/VBA, Python (Matplotlib, Seaborn) **Visualization Tools:** 

# SELECTED PROJECTS / SELF LEARNING (More on GitHub)

Full-Stack Machine Learning Web-App: Mushroom Edibility Predictor

March 2022

Python (SKLearn, Flask, Matplotlib), HTML/CSS/JS

github.com/cdenq/mushroom-edibility-predictor-web-app

- Full-stack web app that utilizes mushroom data to predict edibility of mushrooms with user inputted features
- Trained 7 ML models on 60k+ data points to predict its edibility to within 80-99% accuracy, created 8 EDA graphs

#### Full-Stack Interactive Web Dashboard: Market Metrics on Video Game Industry

January 2022

Python (BS4, Flask, Matplotlib), MongoDB, HTML/CSS/JS (Plotly, Leaflet)

github.com/cdeng/web-dashboard-of-video-game-industry

- Full-stack web app that scraped market metrics on the video game industry and dynamically visualizes based on user input
- Analyzed 10k data points, maintained 5 MongoDB collections, created 19 visualizations

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

**PNC Financial Services Group** Data / Business Analyst Intern

Harrisburg, PA

June 2022 - August 2022

- Contributes to 4+ internal PNC teams across 6 software and data projects to metricize, optimize, and forecast team performance
- Initiative in scaling-and-automation by introducing Python software prototypes to predominantly SQL-driven team
- Attends meetings to understand data requirements, writes efficient SQL to query on-scale, and automates generation of Tableau dashboards

#### California State University: Northridge, College of Engineering and Computer Science

Northridge, CA

Machine Learning Research Assistant (Internship)

November 2021 – May 2022

- Researched graduate-level ML material, edited/created 280+ class slides, 10+ Java-to-Python code conversion samples
- Succeeded in collaborating, designing, and coding for graduate-level ML course curriculum with Professor Wen-chin Hsu

# 2U - Trilogy Education Services, Wyzant.com, Local

Various

Teaching Assistant for Data Science Program, Wyzant AP Computer Science Instructor, Volunteer Tutor

September 2021 - Present

- Teach computer science to 25+ students for 65+ hours in 3+ settings: as TA with 2U bootcamps, freelance instructor, and volunteer tutor
- Succeeding in clearly communicating abstract ideas, listening well to understand students' problems, and adapting teaching style

## **Christie's Auctions & Private Sales**

New York, NY

Gallery Intern / Student

June 2020 - August 2020

- Contributed to 6+ reports, appraisals, and collection package documentation; attended 3+ onsite auctions, hilling meetings
- Succeeded in helping Christie's adjust to accelerated digital marketplace and understand its market role amidst pandemic

#### Oasis Commissary (Non-Profit), University of Pennsylvania

Philadelphia, PA

Founder and Executive Business Operations Manager

September 2016 – March 2020

- Started non-profit to address local community issue in dorm; wrote grant proposal to Dean, obtained vendor license from Philadelphia city
- Start-up succeeded and absorbed by Penn University; managed 21 staff, 2 managers, \$2000 bi-monthly budget, 6 marketing campaigns
- Succeeded in initiating own business development education, serving college dorm 3 years: \$1300 gross, 22k purchases, 180 unique clients

# HOBBIES